SAM TRIPP

CONTACT

✓ sstripps1@gmail.com

in sam-tripp-ca

samtripp.ca

EDUCATION

2016 - 2021 UNIVERSTIY OF WATERI OO

- BSc: Science and Business
- Dean's honour's list achieved every term

SKILLS

- Customer support
- Client relationship management
- · Technical skills
 - Python (OOP, Pandas, Numpy)
 - Frontend (CSS, beginner React)
 - Databases (SQL, Redis, Postgres)
 - Al for coding (chatgpt, GitHub Copilot)
- Project management (incl. Agile Dev)
- Report preparation

INTERESTS

- Yoga (200h certified teacher)
- Running
- Scuba diving
- Hiking
- Guitar (learning)

PROFILE SUMMARY

Driven individual with more than 10 years of experience in a customer facing role. Skilled in identifying client needs, developing tailored strategies, and implementing solutions to deliver an exceptional customer experience. Excellent communicator, with a strong ability to bridge communication between technical and non-technical personnel.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dash Solutions Architect (Intern -> Full Time) 2020 - 2022 *Plotly*

- Worked closely with a variety of clients to build custom software solutions based on their business requirements
- Led the development of production grade web applications, including backend development, frontend design, performance optimization, data management, usability testing, project management
- Presented training workshops on how to use software, catering to users of varying backgrounds and technical skill levels

Portfolio and Product Co-op

2019

Purpose Investments

- Developed financial analytics within Django framework, and used REST API to integrate with internal reporting webpage
- Used python to automate the creation of several daily/weekly reports to increase efficiency of workflow (>1 hour to <10 minutes)
- Completed a variety of ad-hoc tasks across various teams, such as drafting reports, creating slide-decks, and performing financial calculations

Junior Python Engineer

2019

CPP Investments

- Wrote python code for comparison of data between production and test environments, including data visualization
- Quickly adapted to new technologies, workflows, and code repositories in order to complete projects effectively

Various Hospitality Positions

2022 - Present

- · Intentional break from tech for travel and work in hospitality roles
- Worked in various hospitality positions (mostly in Australia) during this time, including barista, server, and fast food shift supervisor